Chokchai Keawthaisong

32/1 Pracha Uthit Road, Rat Burana, Bangkok 10140 Thailand Cell +6689-728-9888 | Chokchai_grand@hotmail.com

SUMMARY

I'm working digital marketer of SCBAM, professional in web design, graphic design, and UX/UI. Experience in the Adobe Creative Suite, responsive design, social media management, data analyses Years of Digital marketing experience: 4

Years of Develop experience: 9

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Mass Communication Technology (2009 – 2013) Rajamangala University of Technology Isan

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Training course

- AWS Cloud Computing (2021)
- Power BI (Intermediate to Advanced) (2019)
- Python for Data Science (2019)
- Tableau data visualization (2018)
- Dynamic Website Design PHP MySQL and JavaScript (2017)
- Full stack Web Development Bootcamp (2017)
- Big Query for Big data engineers (2017)

Certification

- Google Analytics for Beginners (2021)
- Advanced Google Analytics (2021)
- Google Analytics for Power Users (2021)
- Google Analytics 360 (2021)
- Google Tag Manager Fundamentals (2021)
- Introduction to Data Studio (2021)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SCB ASSET MANAGEMENT COMPANY LIMITED / Marketing Strategy Department (September 2017 – Present)

1. Data Analysis & Data Mining

- Provided client report for mutual fund with Power BI, Including cluster segment, user demographics, user behavior metrics and fund analysis. Successful targeting strategy increases buy fund rate by 50% up
- The analysis of the data, it was found that when stimulated with fee-free (front-end fee and management fee) mutual funds Customers will return to buy high value mutual funds in 92 days and account for 75% of customers in the group.

- Oversaw website targeting and pixel implementation through google Tag manager for scbam.com website to ensure the digital data targeting results in optimal reporting for insights that positively impact the business.
- Optimized the data view that enhanced overall performance with the creation of real-time website and Facebook Ads dashboards using Power BI Reports utilizing the data imported from Google Analytics
- Conduct weekly, monthly, and annual mutual fund product reviews and produce customized portfolio analytics report the include performance summary and attribution.
- Present ideas and describe issues or results in a clear, concise, and professional manner to audiences of all job level.
- Analyzed campaigns performances by examining data from database with over 10million records using SQL Server and Power query. Translated the result into actionable recommendations to stakeholders to drive change.
- Analyzing and planning weekly marketing data and reports.
- Managing e-mail campaigns and social media. Contributed to catalogs, mailers, and package inserts.

2. Digital Marketing

- Managed online media campaigns (Google AdWords and Facebook Ads). Developed and managed strategic planning of branded content for mutual fund client and brand social media, actions, and campaigns. Created a social media strategy increasing yearly revenue for business.
- Conversion Rate Optimization increased 40% visitor to lead conversions rate on Google Ads & Organic search channel by implementing SEM to landing pages.
- Manage digital lead acquisition campaigns (mutual fund) through In-house team on Google Ads & Facebook.
- Created multiple SEM campaigns for various accounts and with our decision to maximize its effectiveness, we optimized keywords/ ad copy and saw a 130% increase in total impressions.
- Organized content management including email outreach, blog, social media channels, and website redesign efforts.
- Developed social campaign reporting process, analyzed data and insights to guide strategy for increasing SCBAM brand awareness, website traffic, and user engagement
- Directed organic and paid social strategy for campaign landing page, resulting in an increase in Facebook and Website user impressions by an additional 96% during Q3 2021
- Use Google Analytics and Google tag manager tools to monitor, analyze, and optimize on-page, off-page, traffic trends, SERP rankings, and customer acquisition metrics, through monthly reports.
- Provide seasonal search trends and forecasts to Campaign, Product teams to build product development plans.

3. Develop & Maintain Website

- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed.
- Designed and developed user-friendly website, including optimized check-out page that increased user clicks.
- Developed dynamic and interactive website that ensured high traffic, page views, and User Experience.
- Took ideas from research, too design, and to development using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Created new targeting script, campaign management tools, helps improve UI design.

- Diagnosed errors and implemented solutions.
- Experience working in a fast-paced environment.
- Created a step-by-step process guide for standardized SEO optimizations practiced by the department and utilized by incoming specialist.
- Wrote page of Landing Page scham.com website.
- Support System Line Develop Link Fund Account Line Official and SCBAM Fund Click
- Design Font-End-Website: SCBAM e-Service Project

4. Motion Graphic 2D & 3D / Media Production

- Responsible for creating motion graphic videos and accompanying assets for knowledge and mutual fund campaign on scbam.com
- Creating highly technical content for projection and live events.
- Creating content from Concept and Storyboard to execution and footage delivery.
- Played a key role in executing pitch work to attract new ideas.
- Effectively using Adobe After Effects plug-ins so as to avoid unnecessary expensive render time from 3D software.
- Assisted with the creation and direction of content, tone, and overall style for graphic backgrounds, video edits, and advertisements.
- Acted as a videographer as needed, shooting video for various types of projects.

5. Graphic designer

- Designed a pvd-newsletter monthly magazine for provident fund client.
- Apply creative and design abilities to concept and deliver original content for IPO campaign, print, social media, and website.
- Proof Design Printing
- Wrote copy, created graphics and templates for social media posts, assembly instructions and email marketing
- Reduced media outsourcing by 80% by bringing all photography and social media management in-house resulting in saving company approximately 4-5million bath.
- Recognized by senior management as a talented employee with the ability to take on multiple roles and provide extremely fast turnaround with projects.
- Design Color Scheme for SCBAM Fund Click

Thanachart Bank Public Company Limited (November 2016 – May 2017)

Automotive lending sales management (Marketing)

- Source for quality loans by pre-screening customers to make initial judgment of credit worthiness.
- Plan, coordinate and implement marketing activities for Hire Purchase products to achieve assigned sales target.
- Maintain and build the good rapport with existing business channels, referral agents, and business associates.

Krung Thai Bank Public Company Limited (September 2015 – April 2016)

Bank Teller and Back Office Branch

- Perform Products and Funds Transfer services.
- In charge of Profile Direct Teller System.
- Handle ICAS System.
- Open deposit accounts / FCD.
- Recommend appropriate investments to customers
- Introduce life insurance and non-life insurance packages for customers.

Freelance (January 2013 – September 2017)

IT Support & Technical consultant

- Domain & Hosting
- Setup Cloud AWS (EC2, S3)
- Monitoring Servers
- Web Services (Internal error, too many redirects)
- Web Application Develop
- JavaScript / Vuejs / HTML / CSS / Tailwind / MySQL / Postgres / SQL Server / Oracle / Laravel / PHP

Example Project Freelance

- Setup and setting email marketing system: manager.genomail.net
- Website design project: codepen.io/cc-oo
- Product Landing Page: oneplus.com/uk
- Apple TV Menu Interface (for Chrome, Edge, Safari)
- CSS Animation: Rolex
- Server maintenance: Government and state agency

Motion Graphic 2D & 3D / Media Production

- Video Production
- 3D Rigging / 3D Animation
- Time-lapse Movie
- VDO Photographer / Editor

Graphic Designer 2D & 3D

- 3D Graphic
- 3D Product Mockup
- Abstract Vector
- Magazine Design
- Vector Drawing

Photographer (Medium Format Camera)

- Product Photo
- Studio Portrait
- Stock Photo